


















    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    

    
        
    












<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"  xml:lang="en"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://jack-sides.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        

        <description>Computer Engineering | Computer Science</description>

        
            <language>en</language>
        

        
            <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 21:33:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        

        <link>https://jack-sides.com/</link>

        

        <title>Jack Sides</title>

        

        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/jetta.jpg"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


<p><strong>Project overview:</strong>
Cars are probably what originally sparked my interest in engineering. I started modifying my cars as soon as I got my first car at 16. Since then, I have acquired 3 cars and each of them has had a tremendous amount of work put into it. I&rsquo;ve done everything from replacing headlight bulbs to full engine rebuilds on these cars. The car in the picture to the left is a 1992 VW Jetta that has a VR6 engine swap. I also have a 1993 Eagle Talon TSI AWD which I am in the process of rebuilding the engine on. As for my daily driver, I have a 2002 Subaru WRX, which was my first car, and sparked my interest in cars and engineering in general. These cars are a way for me to take my problem-solving skills from engineering school and apply them to real life projects. Knowing how to do repairs myself has saved me thousands of dollars in repairs and has taught me a great deal about how these machines work.</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:jack-sides.com,2023-12-10:2023-12-10T21:33:03-07:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/cars/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 21:33:03 -0700</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Car modification and building</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                
                    
                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/mcd_picture.png"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


<p><strong>Project overview:</strong> <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
The MCD (Maker&rsquo;s competition of Design) is a 4-person project for the Fundamentals of Engineering II class taken by all engineering majors in the Spring of their Freshman year. The entire process took about 2 months from start to finish. The project started with rough idea brainstorming and collecting data from other college students. Once we have a basic idea of what is needed and what is feasible, we needed to draw 10 different conceptual designs with key features for different projects and pick one of them based with a vote. Once a design is picked, we needed to 3D model the product, build a prototype, design the wiring and circuitry, and program the Arduino microcontroller to create a fully functioning prototype. Once the prototype was finished, we needed to create product posters and a design document, than showcase it to the class. Our group was split into two groups: programming and wiring, and 3D modeling and design. I was on the wiring and programming part of the team with one other person. We ended up programming an entire menu system that was controlled by a rotary encoder and a button. The menu system had tons of features such as audio feedback for button presses, a randomized daily bible verse, states for configuring and setting up specific blinds profiles, and a fully functional clock with a time set feature. The entire product was programmed on an Arduino Uno microcontroller and ended up being around 1200 lines of code.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/mcd_product_design.pdf">Product design document PDF linked here</a></p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:jack-sides.com,2023-12-10:2023-12-10T21:33:03-07:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/mcd/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 21:33:03 -0700</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Maker’s Competition of Design Project</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                
                    
                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/engine_photo.jpg"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


<p><strong>Project overview:</strong> <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
The air engine project is the main project that freshman engineering students at George Fox do in their first term. The basic idea is that you create an oscillating air engine (wobbler engine) from scratch with the tools and materials provided by GFU. In the project, students are expected to come up with an initial concept that is focused on one of 5 goals: speed, cost, torque, efficiency, or coast. The students also need to derive equations for the size relations between parts, create hand drawings with specific measurements, make a bill of materials that does not exceed the budget of $33, create a 3d model of the engine, use the 3d model of the engine to create drawings for machining, machine and assemble the engine, and finally, showcase your engine and compete in the category that you selected. Needless to say, it&rsquo;s a massive project for first year engineering students.</p>
<p>For my engine, I ended up making an inline 3-cylinder engine. Several people have tried this design before, but mine was the second one in the 19-year history of this project to work. Because of this, my engine was showcased as one of the best engines of the class, and I&rsquo;ve now donated it to the engineering department to show prospective students what is possible.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/air_engine_project.pdf">More in-depth PDF linked here</a></p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:jack-sides.com,2023-12-10:2023-12-10T21:33:03-07:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/air_engine/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 21:33:03 -0700</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Oscillating Air Engine</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                
                    
                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/game_ss.png"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/top_down_ss.png"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>

</p>
<p><strong>Project overview:</strong> <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Making video games is a passion of mine, and it helps me apply the things that I have learned in computer science classes in a way that is meaningful to me. I have done all the development of my games in C# in the Visual Studio Code IDE using the Unity game engine. Most of my projects have been to challenge myself and experiment with different concepts. Some of the games that I&rsquo;ve made include a side-scrolling parkour game, a virtual reality bowling game, and a 2D top-down shooter game made with no external plugins. These projects have improved my problem-solving abilities and, of course, my coding expertise.
<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:jack-sides.com,2023-12-10:2023-12-10T21:33:03-07:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/video_game/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 21:33:03 -0700</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Video Game Design</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>If you have any questions or inquiries, please don&rsquo;t hesitate to contact me!</p>
<p><strong>Email:</strong> <a href="mailto:jack.0.sides@gmail.com">jack.0.sides@gmail.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Linkedin:</strong> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jack-sides/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jack-sides/</a></p>
<p><strong>Portfolium:</strong> <a href="https://portfolium.com/jsides22">https://portfolium.com/jsides22</a></p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >https://jack-sides.com/contact/</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/contact/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Contact Me</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/electrathon_car_full.jpg"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/electrathon_instrumentation.jpg"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>

</p>
<p><strong>Project overview:</strong>
Electrathon is a racing event that involves creating the most efficient racecar possible. The goal of the event is to complete as many laps as possible within one hour while only being supplied with 1 kWh of power. At George Fox, there is a team of about 5 people that work on the car.</p>
<p>My job on the team is to repair and redesign the driver&rsquo;s instrumentation. The instrument panel needs to display 4 main things: estimated time left before batteries die, current speed, battery voltage, and temperatures. The instrumentation is controlled by an Arduino Mega through an I2C interface. For my redesign, I designed and modeled a new instrument pod and faceplate for the LCDs to sit in, and replaced the Arduino Nano that was controlling the RGB lights to indicate temperatures. This project is still underway, so the housing for the LCDs is not finished yet.</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >https://jack-sides.com/projects/electrathon/</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/electrathon/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Electrathon Car</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/simon.png"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


<p><strong>Project overview:</strong> <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
The Simon project is the final project for the Digital Logic Design class, which is a class for Sophomore computer and electrical engineering students. Simon is an electronic game of short-term memory skill. The goal of the game is to memorize the order that the buttons light up and then repeat the button inputs by memory. Each time you complete a round, the game repeats, but with one more light in the order each time.</p>
<p>The goal of this project was to create a functional prototype from start to finish with only rough design requirements, like what would be given by a customer. The project was a two-person project. The design requirements that we were given had several features to implement into the device. These features were things such as a functional menu system, score keeping, pseudo-random lighting order, several &ldquo;cheat modes&rdquo; for testing, and, of course, the game itself. The project combines FPGA programming in Verilog, finite state machines, clock timing, and hardware control into one large project.</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >https://jack-sides.com/projects/simon/</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/simon/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>FPGA Simon Project</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[















































    



    

    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        

        
    
        

        
            

    



    







    





    



    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://jack-sides.com/assets/maker_camp.jpg"   style="float:left; height: auto; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-right: 20px; max-width: 100%; width: 50%"   >
</span>


<p><strong>Project overview:</strong>
The George Fox Maker Camps are hosted by a group on campus called the Engineering Ambassadors. The Engineering Ambassadors are all students in engineering at George Fox who want to help pre-college students of all ages learn about STEM and engineering. I am one of the 5 leaders that plan and coordinate events with schools in the Portland/Salem area.</p>
<p>As for the Maker Camps, they are done over the summer and cater towards high school students who are interested in engineering. There are usually 2-3 camps per summer. Each of the camps is usually based on a different focus in engineering, for example, this last year we did 3 camps. One of the camps had the students create automatons, which is a mechanical engineering focus. The other two camps were based on hydraulics and sensors, targeting civil engineering and computer/electrical engineering respectively.</p>
<p>This last summer, I was one of the staff members that was present for all 3 of the camps. For the last camp that was focused on sensors, I was the lead coding instructor, showing the campers how to program Arduinos and make circuits. For this job, I was also in charge of making interactive examples to demonstrate what each sensor does in a fun way. The image on the left is of 3 of the demo pieces that I made for this camp.</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >https://jack-sides.com/projects/maker_camps/</guid>

                
                    <link>https://jack-sides.com/projects/maker_camps/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Maker Camps</title>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
